Namu
Amida
Butsu
Believe it or not, the world is
filled with strange phenomena
（ナレーション）
世の中には いまだに
科学では解明できない怪奇現象が
that science is yet to explain.
確かに存在する
And when people come face to face with them,
人々は それらと出くわしたとき
なすすべもなく ただ
恐怖の闇に突き落とされてしまう
they are helplessly thrown
into the dark depths of fear.
But there are those who fight every day
そんな混沌(こんとん)とした闇に
ひと筋の光をさすべく
to shine a ray of hope
into that chaotic darkness.
日々 戦い続ける者たちがいた
People call them...
人は彼らを こう呼んだ
Psychics
Psychics.
“霊能力者”と
There's no doubt about it...
（依頼人）
あれは間違いない
この世の者(もん)じゃなかった
What I saw was not of this world.
I knew there was something
wrong with this property
もともと この土地は
何かのいわくつきで―
since I bought it dirt cheap.
格安で買ったんです
そういうのは気にしない
性分だったので
I've never been the type to
worry about stuff like that.
畑に異常が起きるのは
いつも収穫前なもんで
But fields are at their most vulnerable
in the days leading up to a harvest.
夜中にふと気になって
So I got worried one night,
went to check on things,
and that's when I saw it.
様子を観察しに出たら
Something was wriggling back and forth,
dancing on my fields!
私の畑の上で 何者かが
くねくねと踊っていたんです
翌朝 農作物は
全て枯れ果てていました
The next morning, I found
all of my crops withered away.
I only started farming to kill time,
but this has been going on for three years.
暇潰しに始めた畑ですが
Amino Acid Fertilizer
Potting Compost
３年も立て続けにこんな具合だと
さすがに気味が悪くて
It's starting to creep me out now.
My next harvest is coming up,
so that's why I gave you a call.
今度の収穫時期も そろそろですし
そこで あなたに電話したんです
I figured I needed the help of
someone with psychic powers.
ここは霊能力のある方に
解決を委ねてみようと
（霊幻(れいげん)新隆(あらたか)）
正しい判断です
A wise decision, sir.
But, you see...
（依頼人）
しかし ちょっとですね
Next year, my idiot son will be
starting high school, so...
来年は うちのバカ息子が
高校でして その…
As for your fees...
報酬が…
You don't think you can pay?
払えそうにないと？
It would depend on how much, but...
（依頼人）
額にもよりますけど…
Well, I am running a business here,
こちらも商売ですからね
それなりの対価を
頂かないことには…
so I'm going to need
some form of compensation.
Executing the Exorcism!!
We will do our best to reduce the spirit possessing you
Option A — Trial Course
A Mere 2,000 yen (Tax Excluded)
Outside Offer Period: 3,980 yen
Option B — Serious Course
A Mere 5,000 yen (Tax Excluded)
Outside Offer Period: 8,980 yen
Option C — All-Out Course
A Mere 12,000 yen (Tax Excluded)
Outside of Offer Period: 19,880 yen
Refer us to a friend now and get an extra 5% reduction!!
Also get an add-on exorcism for 20% off!!
（依頼人）
は… はい
Right...
Let's see. If I'm able to exorcise
whatever it is that's haunting your fields...
（霊幻）
そうですねえ
この畑に巣くう何かを退治できたら
I'll take 30 percent of your upcoming harvest!
次の収穫物の30パーセントを頂く
He's okay with veggies as payment?
（依頼人）
報酬 野菜でいいんだ？
I looked into this a bit on my own,
（霊幻）
俺なりに調べてみたが
肥料や土には問題なさそうだ
but I don't see any issues
with the fertilizer or the soil.
Meaning there's not much
I can do about this situation.
そうなると
俺にはお手上げだからな
What do you think, Mob?
どう思う モブ？
Again, could you not summon me
on such short notice?
（モブ）
だから いきなり呼び出すの
やめてくださいって
This could be the work of
those daikon fairies.
（霊幻）
大根の妖精の仕業かもな
Do those even exist?
（モブ）
そんなの いるんですか？
ん？　今 何か動いたか？
Did you see something move just now?
Actually...
確かに 弱いけど霊気がありますね
It's rather weak,
but I do sense an aura.
（かかし）
昼の会話も聞こえていたぞ
I heard you yappin' earlier today, too.
You gonna exorcise me?
わしを退治するだと？
Mob, let's take care of this quickly.
モブ 早いとこ終わらせちまおう
（モブ）
はい
Okay.
Is that it?
終わりか？
Yes. It was just possessing the scarecrow,
so it probably couldn't do much harm.
はい
かかしに入ってただけで―
害は そんなに
なかったんじゃないかな
What the heck is that?
（霊幻）
何だ こりゃ？
Oh, that would be the spirit's true form.
（モブ）
あっ 霊の本体ですね
So the scarecrow was a decoy?!
（霊幻）
かかしは おとりだったのか！
ぶはっ！　ああ～！
High-Level Spirit
Wriggle Wriggle
This is my land, and I won't
let anyone else have it!
（くねくね）
ここは わしの土地じゃ
何人(なんぴと)にも渡さん！
だったら 権利書を見せろ！
Then show me the deed!
Do you have any idea how hard it is
to grow crops until harvest?
収穫まで育てるのに―
どれだけの手間がかかると
思ってんだ！
Talk about a twisted way to harass someone!
ひねくれた嫌がらせだな！
It's not like I'm letting
the crops go to waste.
（くねくね）
実った野菜を
ムダにしているわけではない
Did you actually think
that spirits can't eat?
お主は霊が食事できんと
思っとるか？
You guys don't need nutrients!
（霊幻）
お前らに栄養は必要ないだろ！
I can absorb the lifeforce of all the crops
that grow in these fields.
（くねくね）
畑で育った野菜の生気を
吸い取ることはできる
So don't worry. They're serving
their purpose as my food.
ちゃんと わしの糧になっとるわ
You wretched vegetable thief...
野菜泥棒め
モブ！　吹っ飛ばせ！
Mob!
Blast him!
（モブ）
はい
Okay.
Not bad, kid.
やるな 小僧
But it appears your friend here
is as ordinary as they come.
じゃが もう１人のほうは
凡人と見た
Master!
師匠！
I'll turn you both into fertilizer!
（くねくね）
２人とも わしの肥料にしてやろう
ムダじゃ
It's no use!
What you're destroying is but
a tiny portion of the plants I control.
お主が破壊している物は―
わしが操っている植物の
ほんの一部にすぎん
だが それ以上やってみろ
But keep it up, and I'll instantly kill
your friend and rip him to pieces!
今すぐ この男をくびり殺して
バラバラにしてやる
You're indeed a child.
（くねくね）
やはり わっぱか
How naïve. You should've known
you were both going to die anyway.
甘い　どうせ死ぬというのに
Since destroying the vines
doesn't hurt the spirit itself,
（モブ）
つるを切っても
本体にダメージがないってことは
it must not be possessing them.
憑依(ひょうい)してるわけでもないんだ
It's controlling living things
like a remote control car.
生き物をラジコンみたいに
操作してる
I've never even thought about doing that.
そんなの 考えたこともなかった
I wonder if I can do it, too...
The same thing as an evil spirit.
僕にもできる？　悪霊と同じこと
You brat!
（くねくね）
小僧！
お？　植物が動きを止めた？
The plants stopped moving?
I tried ordering the plants.
（モブ）
植物に命令してみたんです
When I sent them a stronger signal
than the evil spirit,
悪霊よりも強い念波を
送り込んでみたら
I was able to control them.
操ることができました
それが正解だ
That's the correct solution.
I'm glad you were able to realize it.
（霊幻）よく気づいたな
（爆音）
Curse you, you brat!
（くねくね）
ク… クソ！　小僧！
How dare you overwrite
my command over these plants?!
植物への支配を上書きしおって！
Damn it... You'll pay for this!
おのれ 許さん！
Die!
死ね～！
What?!
Huh?
What is that?
（モブ）
何ですか それ？
I thought I'd start a home garden.
家庭菜園を始めてみる
If it works out, we can save money on food.
うまくいけば
食費の節約になるだろ？
Spirits and Such
Consultation Office
The veggies we were supposed to
get as payment were a bust,
報酬の収穫野菜は
木っ端みじんになってしまったが
but he gave me some soil, fertilizer,
and vegetable seeds instead.
3 times a day!
Organic Fertilizer
Liquid
Fertilizer
Humus
代わりに土や肥料や野菜の種を
もらい受けた
Oh, and here. Your pay for that last job.
お前にも ほら
前回のバイト代だ
Broccoli seeds.
ブロッコリーの種
I'm getting paid in kind now...
（モブ）
ついに現物支給に…
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございます
Oh, right.
（霊幻）
ああ そうだ
I planted some cherry tomatoes in here.
こっちに
ミニトマトの種を植えたんだが
Why don't you put some energy into it
and see if you can make them grow?
試しに これにエネルギーを送って
野菜 成長させてみろよ
はい
Okay.
おお～ スゲえ！
Whoa, that's amazing!
（霊幻）
これは新たなビジネスの予感！
I smell a new business opportunity!
If you have 3 evil spirits,
the exorcism fee on 1 of
them will be on the house!!
This Month Only
Let's see...
あ～む
味…
It tastes like crap.
Umami 0%
You can take these cherry
tomatoes home with you.
このミニトマト
持って帰っていいぞ
Huh?
Mob Psycho
Welcome, my fellow upper echelon members
of the Psycho Helmet Religion.
（信者）
え～ それでは
サイコヘルメット教 幹部会
We're Looking For Our God.
The Psycho Helmet Religion
Let us begin our twelfth official meeting.
第12回を始めたいと思います
本日の議題につきましては
As for today's agenda,
we'll be discussing the head temple
for our Psycho Helmet Religion.
我々 サイコヘルメット教の
総本山についてです
Actually, before we get into that,
I have a question.
（信者）
はい その前に
ちょっといいですか？
Has there been any progress in
the search for our beloved founder?
教祖様の行方について
捜索活動に進展はあったのですか？
He has not been found yet.
（信者）
まだ見つかっていません
Many men have claimed to be the founder,
but they were all impostors.
（米里(めざと)イチ）
何人かの男が
教祖を名乗り出てはいますが
どれも偽者でした
At the (LOL) gathering,
（笑）(カッコワライ)の集会所にて―
いちばん近くで彼を見ていた私が
確認しているので
I saw his face up close,
so I'm the one verifying these claims.
I can guarantee they are false.
間違いありません
But I promise to bring our founder
before you very soon.
ですが そう遠くないうちに
必ず教祖様を連れてきますよ
（米里）
な～んちゃって
Yeah, right. I know the kid to begin with.
最初から正体は
知り合いなんだけどね
I'm going to keep riling up these believers
この信者たちを
もっと盛り上がらせて
and make Mob-kun a cult star.
先にモブ君を
カルトスターにしておくのよ
でも 問題は当の本人
But the biggest obstacle here
is Mob-kun himself.
Right now, there's no way
he could lead anyone.
今のままじゃ
人の上に立つなんて絶対無理
I need him to grow more as a person.
彼には
もっと成長してもらわないと
There has to be a way...
Something that'll make Mob-kun grow.
何かないかしら？
モブ君が成長できるような
イベントは…
（神室(かむろ)真司(しんじ)）
え～ 私 神室真司は―
I...
Kamuro Shinji,
hereby resign from my position
as student council president as of today.
本日をもって
生徒会長を辞任いたします
What?
（徳川(とくがわ)）何だと？
（影山(かげやま) 律(りつ)）えっ！
I spread false rumors about fellow students
（神室）
私の独断で
でっち上げのウワサを流し
and accused them of crimes they didn't
commit, and that's why I'm resigning.
一部生徒に無実の罪を着せた責任を
負っての判断です
Therefore, an election for the next student
council president will be held very soon.
したがって 近日中に
次期生徒会長選を開催します
That's it! This is perfect!
Something to help Mob-kun grow!
（米里）
あったわ　これよ これ！
モブ君の成長イベント！
でも モブ君に出馬する動機が
何もない
But there's no reason
Mob-kun would want to run.
どうしたら…
How do I...
フフ～ン
I wonder who the next
president is going to be.
（ジャガイモ）
次の会長 どうなるんだろね？
（高嶺(たかね)ツボミ）
ね～
Right?
I just hope they're a good person,
if nothing else.
でも とりあえず
まともな人がいいよね
（モブ）
ああっ ツボミちゃんだ
Ah, it's Tsubomi-chan.
She's as cute as ever.
今日も かわいいなあ
だから見過ぎだって！
You're staring way too hard again.
はっ！　米里さん！
Mezato-san?!
And you're panicking too much.
慌て過ぎ
ふ～ん やっぱり高嶺さんのこと
好きなんだ？
So you do like Takane-san.
Wha... How did you...
ちょっ！　なんで知って…
What's with that reaction?
なんだ そのリアクション！
I never expected you to
fall for the school's idol.
しっかし モブ君
あんな学校のアイドルに
ほれるなんて
I guess even you can be
rather superficial, too.
意外と俗っぽいところがあるね
I honestly don't get
what you see in her, though.
（米里）
正直 どこがいいのか
全然 共感できないけど…
I've been friends with Tsubomi-chan
since we were little.
ツボミちゃんは幼なじみだよ
Oh, she's the school's idol?
え？　学校のアイドルだったのか
I see...
そっか
How did two childhood friends end up
in such drastically different situations?
幼なじみが どうして
ここまで差がついたのか
Under normal circumstances,
you'd have no chance with her,
普通なら モブ君が
彼女とうまくいくなんて
ありえないんだけど
but right now, you have a
once-in-a-lifetime opportunity!
今 絶好のチャンスが
訪れているわよ
What do you mean?
どういうこと？
Student Council
The seat of student council
president is vacant!
（米里）
生徒会長の椅子が
空いてるじゃない
Right now, Takane-san is
way out of your league,
今のモブ君じゃ
高嶺さんとは釣り合わないけど
but what if you were
student council president?
もしモブ君が生徒会長だったら
どう思う？
Student Council President
箔(はく)がつくと思わない？
You'd go shooting up the ranks!
You might be able to close the gap
between you and your school idol!
あの学校のアイドルと
距離を縮められるかもしれないわよ
I wouldn't mind helping you out
if you're thinking about running.
出馬するなら
協力してあげてもいいよ
You'll owe me one, though.
ただし 貸しにしとくけどね
This is the perfect opportunity to show
people who you really are, Mob-kun!
男を上げる
またとないチャンスだよ モブ君！
Hardcore Training Montage
And on that day,
Mob's hardcore training began.
（ナレーション）
その日から
モブの猛特訓が始まった
Finally, a week later...
そして １週間後
Student Council President Candidate Speech Competition
We will now begin the election to decide
our next student council president.
（司会者）
それでは これより
次期生徒会長選を
始めたいと思います
There are a total of four candidates.
候補者は全部で４名です
Our first candidate is
Morishige Kyohei-kun from Class 2-2.
まず１人目 ２年２組 森重恭平(もりしげきょうへい)君
Each candidate gave their speech.
（ナレーション）
こうして 候補者による演説が
開始された
Next, from Class 3-4,
（司会者）
続きまして ３年４組 神室真司君
we have Kamuro Shinji-kun.
Wait, why?
あれ？　なんで また？
自分で辞めたのに？
Didn't he resign?
President, why did you resign
without discussing it with us?
（律）
会長 なぜ相談もせず１人で？
I'm just as responsible for what we did!
だったら僕にも責任が！
Resigning is no way to take responsibility.
（徳川）
辞めるなんて
責任を取ったことにはならん
You're still running away,
which achieves nothing.
これ以上 逃げてどうする？
Stand for election again,
and if you do get elected...
もう一度 立候補しろ
もし当選したら そのときこそ…
Yeah. That'll be my opportunity
to truly make things right.
（神室）
ああ 反省を生かすときだ
And finally, Mob's turn arrived.
（ナレーション）
そして ついに
モブに出番が回ってきた
Nii-san?
（律）
兄さん？
What the heck is he doing?
（暗田(くらた)トメ）
あいつ 何やってんの？
Wait, Mob-kun?
えっ モブ君？
You practiced your speech over and over,
not to mention I basically wrote it for you.
（米里）
演説の練習は重ねたし
私が用意した文言もある
You've got this!
勝てるわよ！
Kageyama! It's all about guts!
（郷田(ごうだ)武蔵(むさし)たち）
影山 気合いだ～！
You pulled a fast one on me,
White T Poison.
（鬼瓦天牙(おにがわらてんが)）
さすが白Ｔポイズン
表からも この学校を牛耳る気か！
You're not content with ruling
the school from the shadows?
I was planning on supporting
President Kamuro,
（律）
神室会長を
支持するつもりだったけど
but this changes everything.
こうなったら 話が別だ
Kageyama Shigeo-kun from Class 2-1.
（司会者）
２年１組 影山茂夫(しげお)君
それでは どうぞ
Please begin.
ハア～
And it's over.
（米里）
終わった
Each candidate is given five minutes
for their campaign speech,
（ナレーション）
１人５分間の
与えられたスピーチの時間
ひと言も発さずに終わるのは
前代未聞のことであった
and he was the first person ever
to not say a single word in that time.
Student Council President Election
Voting Results
1st Kamuro
2nd Nakayama
3rd Morishige
4th Kageyama
（米里）
ハア～
He won't cut it as the founder like this.
これじゃあ
まだ教祖には なれないわね
I need him to be better.
もっと立派になってくれないと
I never should've done that.
余計なこと しなきゃよかった
This one did a number on him.
（志村(しむら)）
影山 今回のは こたえてるな
He's not moving at all.
（隈川(くまかわ)）
全然 動かん
Go on home for the day, okay?
（郷田）
今日は もう帰れ　な？
Telepathy Club
Body Improvement Club
Yes, sir. I'm very sorry.
（モブ）
はい すみません
I'll be waiting for you behind the school.
W-Wait, this is...
こ… このパターンは…
When I saw you muster the courage to take
the podium despite being so uncomfortable,
（エミ）
苦手なのに勇気を出して
壇上に立つ姿を見て
I ended up falling for you, Kageyama-kun.
影山君のこと
好きになっちゃいました
Um...
あの…
Please go out with me.
私とつきあってください
Progress Toward
Mob's Explosion
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 21%
II
Mob Psycho
Telepathy Club
Body Improvement Club
（エミ）
影山君
Kageyama-kun.
一緒に帰ろう
Let's walk home together.
Oh, but I have club...
あ… 僕 部活が…
Go on, Kageyama.
Today's menu is free training, anyway.
（郷田）
行ってこい 影山！
今日は自主トレだ
すいません 武蔵部長
Thank you, Captain Musashi.
Huh?
はあ？
モブ君に彼女が出来ただあ？
Mob-kun has a girlfriend?
What's going on? Is this some
supernatural phenomenon?
（雉子林(きじばやし)）
どういうことだ？　怪奇現象か？
What the heck's happening?
（犬川(いぬかわ)）
一体 何が起きてるというんだ？
But man, I'm so envious...
（猿田(さるた)）
でも うらやましいっす
So what do you usually do, Kageyama-kun?
（エミ）
影山君 ふだんは何してるの？
（モブ）
ん… え～っとね
肉体改造部で走ったりしてるよ
Um...
I do some running with
the Body Improvement Club.
Other than that, I help
an acquaintance with their work.
あとは知り合いの仕事
手伝ったり…
どんな？
What kind of work?
Huh? Oh, ghost—
え？　幽れ…
I-It's sort of like a bookstore.
あっ ああ… 本屋さんみたいな感じ
What? You work part-time at
a bookstore, Kageyama-kun?
えっ？　影山君って
本屋でアルバイトしてるの？
すご～い！
That's amazing!
N-No, it's not a big deal...
い… いや 別に
その… すごくはないよ
I only help out with really simple things.
ホント簡単な手伝いだけだから
Still, it is amazing!
I'd love to work at a bookstore.
すごいよ　私も本屋で働きたいなあ
I'm already lying to her.
（モブ）
いきなりウソをついてしまった
But I think telling her I have
an exorcism job will creep her out.
でも 除霊バイトなんて
気味悪がられる気がする
You look a little pale. Are you okay?
（エミ）
顔色 悪いよ　大丈夫？
Yeah. Hey, you like books, Emi-san?
あの… エミさんは本が好きなの？
Well... I do like books, but...
（エミ）
うん 本 好き
I guess I don't mind telling you,
Kageyama-kun.
影山君なら 言ってもいいかな
I'm writing a novel.
私ね 小説とか書いてるの
（モブ）
えっ！　へえ すごいね
Huh?
Wow, that's amazing!
What's amazing about that?
（エミ）
何がすごいの？
あっ 興味なかった？　ごめんね
Oh, you don't care, huh?
Sorry.
あっ… いや ホントに
すごいと思ったんだけど
No, I really think it's amazing!
I'm just bad with words.
ほかに感想が思いつかなくて
フフ 今度 読んでもらおうかな
Maybe I'll have you read it sometime.
見せるの初めてだし
相当 恥ずかしいんだけど
I haven't shown anyone else,
so it'd be pretty embarrassing for me.
But this counts as practice, too.
これも練習！
Sure, I'll read it.
（モブ）
うん 読むよ！
And every day after that,
Mob walked home from school with Emi.
（ナレーション）
それから毎日 モブは
エミと一緒に下校した
Hey, Mob. You're home early again.
（エクボ）
おう モブ！　今日も早いな
Did you quit your club?
最近 部活 やめちまったのか？
No, I'm actually heading back to school now.
ううん 今から学校 戻るよ
Huh?
Why the heck did he
bother coming home, then?
なんで 一旦 帰ってきてんだ？
Hey, Mob. You seem more
cheerful than usual today.
おう モブ
なんか今日 表情 明るくねえか？
You exorcism game is on point, too.
除霊もノリノリだし
（悪霊のうめき声）
（モブ）そうですか？
You think so? I can't really tell myself.
分かりませんけど
Did you get a girlfriend?
（霊幻）
彼女でも出来たか？
なんてな ハハハ…
As if!
I-I'm done with the exorcism,
so I'm going home now.
（モブ）
じょ… 除霊 終わったんで
先 帰りますね
うっ！　それじゃあ
Bye.
Huh?
What?
お代わり
Seconds, please.
Wow, this is rare.
Our Shige asking for seconds.
（モブの母）
あら 珍しい　茂(しげ)がお代わりなんて
What's up, Shigeo? Did you use
too much of your psychic powers?
（モブの父）
どうした 茂夫？
超能力でも使い過ぎたか？
いや そんなんじゃないよ
No, it's not like that.
（律）
兄さん この前の選挙で
落ち込んでると思ったけど
I thought Nii-san would be
bummed out about the election,
but I'm glad to see he's more than fine.
なんか元気そうで よかった
One Week Later
Are you done reading?
そろそろ読み終わった？
どうかな？
What do you think?
It's really good... I think.
面白い… ような気がする
You know a lot of big words.
いろんな言葉 知ってるんだね
If you don't get it, just say so.
分からないなら
分からないって言いなよ
あ… ごめん　違うんだ
Sorry! That's not what I meant!
I really did pay attention to every word!
適当に読んだわけじゃなくって…
Say, Kageyama-kun...
ねえ 影山君
It's been a week since I asked you out.
私が影山君に告白してから
今日で１週間なんだけど
You rejected me then,
so why do you still walk home with me?
どうして断ったのに
一緒に帰ってくれるの？
Is it because you felt bad for me?
私のこと かわいそうだと
思ったから？
Huh? No, it's nothing like that.
えっ いや
そういう あれじゃなくって
I also know you were going back
to your club after you got home.
帰ったあとで部活に戻ってるのも
知ってたよ
You keep trying not to hurt my feelings.
私に気を遣ってばっかり
Are you sure it's not pity?
I feel sort of pathetic.
同情かな？　なんか惨めな気持ち
I-I'm sorry. That's not my intention.
（モブ）
ご… ごめん
そんなつもりじゃないよ
And all you do is apologize.
謝ってばっかり
I don't understand how you feel at all.
影山君の気持ち 全然 分かんないよ
Or could it be...
それか もしかして
自分の気持ち 持ってないの？
that you don't even have feelings?
Huh?
（エミ）
自分の意見とかさ
Like, your own opinions.
Your froze up in your campaign speech, too.
ガチガチに緊張してた
選挙スピーチもさ
Did you only run for president
because someone told you to?
立候補したのも 誰かに言われて
やったことなんじゃないの？
Well...
あのね 実は
私も そういうとこあるんだ
The truth is,
I'm sort of like that, too.
You are?
そうなの？
The reason I asked you out
was because of a dare.
（エミ）
告白したのも
本当は罰ゲームなんだ
We thought your silent speech was hilarious,
無言スピーチを見て面白がって
友達とジャンケンして負けたの
so my friends and I played
rock-paper-scissors, and I lost.
I was afraid I'd be a laughingstock
if you turned me down,
振られたら 逆に私が
すっごい笑い者にされるから
怖かったけど
but since you started walking home with me,
they never found out you actually did.
一緒に帰ってくれたから
振られたのバレなかった
Thanks.
（エミ）ありがとう
（バイブ音）
But I figured it was about time I told you.
もうそろそろ 時間がたったから
言わなきゃと思って
Sorry for lying to you for the past week.
１週間もダマしてて ごめんね
A novel? Seriously? You're too funny!
（女子生徒１）
なに 小説とか
マジウケんだけど こいつさ～
Let me read it!
読ましてみ
うわっ 超書いてるじゃん
何 これ？
Damn, you wrote a lot! What the hell?
アハハハ！
ちょっと勝手に広げないでよ
Hey, come on. Don't just read it like that.
It's really embarrassing.
マジ恥ずかしいから！
（女子生徒１）
ふ～ん
Are you actually writing
this seriously, Emi?
エミ これ本気で書いてんの？
Of course not. I was just a little bored.
違う違う！
ちょっと暇だったから
How bored could you possibly be
to write this crap?
どんだけ暇なんだよ　えい！
Instead of wasting your time writing
this drivel, go to the arcade with us!
いつも こんなん書いてるなら
ゲーセンつきあえ！
（エミ）
いつもじゃないってば
It's not like I spend all my time on it.
Hey, stop that. You're littering.
（女子生徒２）
もう やめてよ
ゴミが散らかるでしょ
もういいよ
No, if you're going to do it,
make sure it's all ripped up.
どうせなら
ちゃんと細かくしてよね
Stop... that.
（モブ）
やめ… なよ
は？　誰？
Who are you?
Kageyama-kun?
（エミ）
影山君
Oh, hey! It's that guy!
（女子生徒３）
あっ こいつ あれじゃん
The one who turned statue during his speech!
（女子生徒３）
スピーチで
地蔵みたいになってたヤツ
Wow, so he can talk.
（女子生徒２）
しゃべれたんだ
What the hell's your problem?
なんなんだよ てめえはよ！
Still think you're dating Emi?
She only asked you out on a dare, dude.
罰ゲームでエミに告られたの
まだマジに取ってんの？
Hilarious.
ウケる
She's not your girlfriend!
お前の彼女じゃねえから！
It's really mean of you to rip up
the novel she worked so hard to write.
頑張って書いた小説を
破くなんて ひどいよ
Huh?
You said it was just to kill time, right?
暇潰しって言ってたじゃんね？
Y-Yeah. Something like that.
う… うん まあね
What the hell's your problem? Get a clue.
（女子生徒１）
なんなんだよ 勘違い男
Scram.
てめえ どっか行けよ！
聞こえねえの？　行けって！
Didn't you hear me? Get outta here!
I don't think this is trash.
（モブ）
僕は これがゴミだなんて思わない
If you're going to throw
it away, I'll take it.
捨てるくらいなら 僕がもらう
自分の気持ちは
大事にすることにしたから
I made the decision to
consider my feelings more.
And you need to pick up
things you feel are important.
大事なものは拾うんだ
Wh-What the hell is he talking about?
（女子生徒１）
な… 何 言ってんの こいつ？
Talk about creepy...
なんか怖～
Emi?!
エミ？
いいから　先 帰ってて
You guys can head home.
Oh, really?
あっそ
Okay, then.
（女子生徒たち）
じゃあね～ バイバ～イ
Bye-bye.
Aw...
あ～あ
何やってんだろ？
What are we even doing?
Wanna chase after them?
追いかける？　アッハハハ…
But... Thank you.
No going back...
でも ありがとうね
Forget this. I can just write it again.
もういいよ　また書けばいいからさ
You see...
僕 超能力者なんだ
Adventure
I happen to be an esper.
Thank you, Kageyama-kun.
（エミ）
ありがとう 影山君
やるじゃん
Smooth.
Ripped Apart
~Someone Is Watching~
（エクボ）
おいおい マジか！
What? Seriously?
If something that fun was going on,
you should've called me!
そんな面白そうなことが
あったなら 呼べよ！
I never would've expected you to show
someone your powers on your own!
自分から他人に
“力”のお披露目するなんて
珍しいじゃねえかよ！
で その後 どうなんだよ？
So, what happened after that?
何が？
What do you mean?
With that Emi girl or whatever.
そのエミちゃんとやら
Did her attitude toward you change
when she saw your powers?
お前の力を見て
態度 変わったとか
Did she go, "I've really fallen for you now,"
or something like that?
〝ホントに好きに
なっちゃった～〞とかよ
That would never happen just
because I have psychic powers.
超能力程度で―
そんなの
あるわけないよ
マジか？　そんなもんか？
Really? Is that how it is?
（エミ）
超能力か～
Psychic powers, huh...
すごいな～ 影山君
Kageyama-kun sure is amazing.
中学生の超能力者
A middle school student...
with psychic powers...
More importantly, you fell
for another love letter?
（エクボ）
つうか お前―
またラブレターにダマされたのかよ
Looks like you'll always need
an advisor like me, Shigeo!
やっぱり茂夫には
俺様という―
アドバイザーが
必要だな！
From now on, I'll always stay by your side!
これからは常に
一緒にいてやっからな！
それは気持ち悪い
That's gross.
You're not nice to me, but I knew that.
（エクボ）
俺様には
優しくないんだよ
知ってんだよ
Progress Toward
Mob's Explosion
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 27%
Improve Your Speech: Waterfall Meditation
Improve Your Speech:
Bears
Japanese Dictionary
Delicious Vegetables
Lifting Weights Is the Best Answer to Everything
How to Properly Read Novels(How to Properly Read Series)
How to Properly Read Social Cues (How to Properly Read Series)
Let's go to Cuticle City
in search of urban legends!
（霊幻）
都市伝説を追って 深爪(ふかづめ)町へゴー
Human-Faced Dog, Dash Granny,
Red Raincoat, the Dragger, and many more!
人面犬 ダッシュ婆(ババア)
赤いレインコート
そして おひきさんと
盛りだくさんだ
I'm leaving the rest to you, Mob!
あとは任せたぞ モブ
Next time on Mob Psycho 100 II Episode 2:
次回「モブサイコ100 Ⅱ」
第２話
“都市伝説　噂(うわさ)との遭遇”
"Urban Legends
~Encountering Rumors~."
Urban Legends
~Encountering Rumors~
Watching II in real time
is also a wise decision.
「Ⅱ」もリアタイが正しい判断です